My brother Cees-Jan and a friend are visiting
Brie..?
Tofu.
I think 4 or 5 o’clock in the morning they start
early, right?
Yeah.
In June... they start at sunrise
That's quite early now.
did you put the chickens inside?
the following footage is from when we were away for 4 days
no luck for the fox
timber for new solar panel frames
that’s fine, 176.2 cm
exactly the same measurement
it’s better for the wood too
I’m gonna give this to you
these are inside measurements
so this one is shorter, because it’s on 25 degree angle
so this is shorter than the frame
Yeah.
it’s pretty
it’s already empty
it’s a neverending story
your mix is ready to go
great
lunch!
ready!
soup?
it does look like pea soup
smells good!
if the sun comes up there we have to make sure that this one does not cast a shadow
and this ones comes until here
my brother and friend are walking up the mountain
trying to see them,
but it's a little hazy.
I might fly up the drone to have a look
I think these are carpenter bees
They're good pollinators.
It's actually quite a big group here.
Which is unusual
because they dig their nests...
into the walls.
But they found a nice spot here
underneath the roof.
I'm going to leave them there
because the...
swarm doesn't
get as big as for example, with wasps
and hornets, which are more of a threat.
But those are fine here.
The males can sting.
They're more aggressive and buzz
around your head, but they can’t sting.
Females can sting,
if the nest is threatened
won't happen here.
A couple of things going on.
The walls are finished,
which is really nice.
Cleaning everything up
and then preparing the floor work
There’s going to be a primer
and then a self-leveling screed.
There’s a bit of cupping,
so I need more material in the middle.
So about 20, 25 bags are going to go in there.
Also leveling out outside
because there are still some soil,
the trenches over there were not completely filled
got a gravel load as well to the trenches on the sides.
it needs some more gravel,
And then the soil in the rest . that needs to be finished first.
And then,
I'll continue on the solar panels again,
building the stands.
Yeah.
Also, the chicks should be coming today.
It's day 21.
Eventually I put them in an electrical hatcher,
which has a rotating floor,
because last year
I did it myself in the box that I made.
But we were on, on the holiday last week,
so, we weren't able to do that.
And this automatic catcher works
perfectly for that
2 of the 4 acts or hatching.
The other two are.
Maybe they're not fertilized.
They stay transparent.
So we're going to have probably two chicks
if everything goes well.
And, so today I'm going to put them in
the bigger box with the lamp
so they can stay on the temperature.
And, in the course of the next weeks,
I would lower the temperature
so they get used to the outside
temperature
I hope... maybe the chickens
come in the middle of the night.
You think so?
I'm going to stay up.
Are you sure about that?
I see no sign of breaking
Maybe they come tomorrow.
Because they lost one day, remember?
they should come today
Yeah, but the fact that was without temperature
Yeah, it’s very unpredictable
they make like a...
they cut like a hole.
anytime soon now
This one is actually starting to grow some plums
Never seen it before.
So let's see if they develop.
Yeah.
I was pouring some footers
separately from where they need to be
because the holes
were not exactly in the right place.
So I'm going to let that cure
and then I can start
building the first,
first set of panels
I expect this one to come first..!
yea she’s a little slow
hiii
we’re starting to help a bit, because this chick has been stuck for a long time, and the membrane is starting to dry out
pfjeww, ok...
I think they're both alright.
The one that cracked the shell first yesterday,
We thought she was going to be out,
but she was kind of stuck
for about six hours or so.
Like, the entire top of the shell was kind
of loose, but she was still stuck and
She started to dry up a bit inside
the shell,
which is not good.
So in the end, we helped her a little bit
with keeping the membrane moist
and freeing her head
And then she came out.
Yeah.
You never know.
I mean,
I think the problem was with this box,
it's harder to keep the humidity.
And because we're constantly
peeking inside and then humidity goes out
when you have this incubator in the bowl,
everything stays inside, and
you can just look at the hatching process
without opening the box.
Would have been probably better.
I might do that next time.
But, Yeah, they’re staying in this box now
they can grow up there
for the coming weeks.
It's a bit bigger. And,
Yeah.
All good.
Okay, guys,
here’s your meal
Please, excuse me.
Excuse me.
Yeah, I don't think the first day they will eat much
they try... they’re checking things out
Chicken things out?